Muhammad Syahrul Nizam

Mshahn323@gmail.com| +62 82268521302 | linkedin.com/in/muhammad-syahrul-nizam-370b51221 | Pekanbaru,Indonesia

PROFIL

Student of Riau University's Department of Business Administration. Have expertise in business development and data analytics, master various tools such as Microsoft Office, Spreadsheet, Figma, and SQL. have good interpersonal skills such as communication, problem solving, and collaboration. I currently want to develop my business development and data analytics skills to a professional level.

EDUCATION

Universitas Riau - Pekanbaru

August 2021-Now (6th Semester)

Bachelor of Business Administration, 3.54 / 4.00

Relevant Courses: Entrepreneurship, Leadership, Business Qualification Studies, Risk Management, and Product and Brand Management.

EXPERIENCE

Wirausaha Kampus Merdeka Batch 2 -Pekanbaru

August 2023 - December 2023

Leader Of Team

- Marticulation (The concept of entrepreneurship is carried out as an e-learning process through LMS. The
 materials studied are: Transformational Leadership, NPEMC Analysis, Root Cause Analysis with Fishbones
 methods, Design Thinking, Project based Learning and Business Model Canvas.
- Online Course and Offline Course (Following online course and offline course with 5 activities namely: Motivation and Mindset Entrepreneur, Idea Generation, Prototyping, Marketing Validation and Unit Product Cost & Pricing Method)
- On Boarding or Business Practice (Identifying business processes and problems encountered by one of the UMKM in New York City)
- Prototype Business (Developing business ideas and establishing effective and efficient marketing strategy)
- Marketing validation and Festival (Validating business ideas through Launching products))

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE

Business Entrepreneurship Manager -Pekanbaru

May 2023- Mar 2024

Himpunan Mahasiswa Administrasi Bisnis

- Design and create new products for the development of Kedai Adbis in business administration.
- Develop and implement innovative strategies to drive growth and profitability of Kedai Adbis
- Build and maintain relationships with other entrepreneurs in the social sciences and political sciences faculties.

Head of the Secretariat Infokom Department -Pekanbaru

Mar 2023 - January 2024

Ikatan Pelajar Mahasiswa dan Pelajar Kota Batam Pekanbaru

- Conduct administrative activities such as making proposals and sop fields as well as being responsible in managing schedules, meetings and invitations for the Infokom division
- Responsible in creating an organization website using wordpress tools.
- Create attractive designs for platforms like Instagram and organizational websites.

Staff of the Cadres Departement IPMKOB-P -Pekanbaru

Mar 2022 - Januari 2023

Ikatan Pelajar Mahasiswa dan Pelajar Kota Batam Pekanbaru

- Contributing to the student framework event organized by IPMKOB-P.
- Contributing to the Improvement of Quality and Skills of IPMKOB-P cadres.
- Host of the IPMKOB-P appointment and confirmation event

CERTIFICATION & COURSE

- Ajukan Pertanyaan untuk Mengambil Keputusan Berdasarkan Data (Google)
- Dasar-dasar Analitik Data: Data, Data di Mana-mana (Google)
- Mempersiapkan Data untuk Eksplorasi (Google)
- Memproses Data dari Kotor ke Bersih (Google)
- Menganalisis Data untuk Menjawab Pertanyaan (Google)
- Wirausaha Kampus Merdeka Batch 2 (Wirausaha Merdeka)
- Digital Marketing Badan Nasional Sertifikasi Profesi (BNSP)
- Latihan Kepemimpinan Managemen Mahasiswa Tingkat Dasar (Universitas Riau)

PROJECT

Leader Of Kuliah Kerja Nyata Muara Lembu - Kuantan Singingi

1 July - 10 August 2024

Building an Environmental Care Character with a Plantation of 1000 Seedlings in Muara Lembu Kuansing

- Successfully completed 14 major work programs, showcasing strong organizational and management abilities.
- Design and create a 1,000-seed planting work program in several institutions and schools in Muara Lembu.
- Implement waste recycling activities for the community, such as the production of ecobricks, the education of students and schoolchildren, and others.
- Established a program promoting clean and healthy living in the village environment, demonstrating commitment to the community development and sustainability.
- Maintaining relationships with Muara Lembu citizens.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: Microsoft Office, Spreadsheet, SQL, Big Query, Figma, WordPress

Management Skills: Project management and planning, problem-solving and decision-making, adaptability and flexibility

Communication Skills: Verbal and written communication, Presentation and Public Speaking

Language: Indonesia, English